rbauction.com 2017-03-18

# Privacy Statement | Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers

  * Home
  * Current Inventory
    * Construction
    * Agriculture
    * Transport Trucks
    * Trailers
    * Vocational Trucks
    * Lifting & Material Handling
    * Vehicles & Buses
    * Asphalt & Concrete
    * Demolition & Recycling
    * Drilling & Mining
    * Aggregate
    * Oil, Gas, Power and Utility
    * Marine, Aircraft & Rail
    * Real Estate
    * Consumer Items
    * Attachments
    * Industrial Support
    * Forestry & Environmental
  * Auction Results
  * Auctions
  * Buying
    * How To Buy
    * Read Before You Bid
    * Bid Deposits & Payments
    * Buyer Services
    * Buying Tips
    * What Buyers Say
  * Selling
    * About our auctions
    * Our solutions
    * Services for sellers
    * Tips & resources
    * Customer testimonials
    * Contact us to sell
  * Financing
    * Truck Financing
    * Heavy Equipment Financing
    * Farm Equipment Financing
    * Working Capital Loans
    * Dealer Solutions
  * My Account
    * Account Summary
    * Auction Activity
    * My Purchases
    * My Equipment
    * Bid Deposits and Payments
    * Financing Applications
    * My Profile
    * Preferences
    * Terms and Conditions
  * Blog
  * Private Treaty
  * About Us
    * History
    * Management
    * Testimonials
    * Health & Safety
    * Environment
    * News Releases
    * For Investors
    * For Media
    * Videos
    * Corporate Governance
  * Contact Us
    * Corporate Offices
    * Agriculture Division
    * Strategic Accounts & European Key Accounts
    * Paid Appraisals
    * Auction Sites and Local Representatives
  * 

This Privacy Statement describes the privacy practices of Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers Incorporated and its affiliates ("RBA") with respect to the collection, use, and disclosure of personal and device information, including in respect of RBA's website located at [www.rbauction.com](https://www.rbauction.com/) and related mobile apps. This Privacy Statement may be supplemented or modified by agreements entered into between RBA and an individual from time to time.

Where RBA has provided a translation of the English language version of this Privacy Statement, such translation is provided for your convenience only. To the extent there is any inconsistency between the English language version of this Privacy Statement and any such translation, the English language version shall govern.

In this Privacy Statement, "personal information" means any information about an identifiable individual, excluding any information that has been made anonymous or that is excluded from the definition of "personal information" under applicable laws.

This statement will notify you of:

  1. What personal information or third party personal information is collected through our website
  2. How the information is used
  3. With whom the information may be shared
  4. What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of personal information
  5. The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of personal information under our control
  6. How you can correct any inaccuracies in your personal information

### Information Collection

RBA collects personal information from individuals through various means, including through RBA's websites, consignment agreements and the bidder registration process. For security reasons, RBA may also utilize audio/video or other surveillance means to monitor its premises from time to time.

Requirements for consent to collection, use, or disclosure of personal information vary depending on circumstances and on the type of personal information that is intended to be collected, used, or disclosed. In determining whether consent is required and, if so, which form of consent is appropriate, RBA will take into account both the sensitivity of the personal information at issue and the purposes for which RBA will use the information. Consent may be express, implied (including through use of "opt-out" consent where appropriate), or deemed. For example, if an individual provides his/her mailing address and requests information regarding a particular product, consent to use the address to mail product information to the individual is implied.

If an individual wishes to withdraw consent to the collection, use, or disclosure of his or her personal information, they may contact Customer Service at [csg@rbauction.com](mailto:csg@rbauction.com) for further information. RBA will inform the individual of the likely consequences of withdrawing his or her consent. Except where otherwise required or permitted by law or contract, RBA will then stop collecting, using or disclosing the individual's personal information.

### Information Use

RBA uses information collected from individuals to provide products or services, to respond to requests for information regarding RBA's products and services, to protect our rights and the rights of others and for additional purposes that may be identified at or before the time that the information is collected. The information gathered will be used for general corporate marketing purposes, thereby enabling RBA to refine and improve our service and better meet our customers' needs.

We also use information collected to deliver relevant content and advertising by: (i) generating and analyzing reports and data about your transactions history, patterns of usage of our websites or after combining your information with information relating to your use of services provided by other members of Ritchie Bros. corporate family; (ii) personalizing our online services based on your customized preferences and usage; and (iii) working with unaffiliated third party service providers who help deliver ds relating to our products and services or products and services offered by other members of the Ritchie Bros. corporate family which we believe are consistent with your interests when using our websites or other unaffiliated websites.

RBA will not use or disclose personal information for purposes other than those for which it was collected, except with the consent of the individual or as required or permitted by law. Once the information is no longer required to fulfill its intended purposes, and is no longer required or permitted to be retained for legal or business purposes, it will be destroyed, erased, or made anonymous.

By using the RBA website and apps

, you agree to allow RBA to use your remarks, suggestions, writings or comments as RBA so determines without your further consent and without compensation or any other interests or rights. However, RBA will not identify the specific source of the comments by name or email address without your permission. To the extent permitted by applicable law, you also agree that RBA will not be liable for use or acquisition of your information by any third party without RBA's knowledge or consent.

### Information Disclosure

Information may be disclosed in accordance with this Privacy Statement or as otherwise permitted or required by applicable law.  Please note that some third party service providers may store information received from us or you outside of your country of residence, and that under the laws of those other jurisdictions, in certain circumstances courts, law enforcement agencies, regulatory agencies or security authorities in those other foreign jurisdictions may be entitled to access your information.  Your use of our products and services or your submission of any information to us will constitute your consent to the transfer of your information outside of your country of residence, which may provide for different data protection rules than in your country. Please contact us at csg@rbauction.com, attention: Privacy Officer, if you have any questions.  We do not disclose your personal information to third parties for their direct marketing and advertising purposes without your explicit consent.  Please also note that an individual may choose not to share certain information as described in "Choice/Opt Out" below.

**Third Parties.** We may use third parties to perform functions in connection with our services online (for example, Google Analytics for data analysis and Marketo for email marketing automation services).  We may share information about you that they need to perform their functions and will take appropriate steps to ensure that such recipients safeguard the personal information and use the information only for authorized purposes. If we partner with another party to provide specific services, and you register for these services, we will share the contact information or other information necessary for the third party to provide the requested services. We may also disclose personal information to legal, financial, and other professional advisors and to our lenders or insurers in connection with the operation of our business where such parties have agreed to confidentiality restrictions.

**Business Changes.** If we become involved in a merger, acquisition, sale of assets, joint venture, securities offering, bankruptcy, reorganization, liquidation, dissolution, or other transaction or if the ownership of all or substantially all of our business otherwise changes, we may share or transfer your information to a third party or parties in connection with such business change.

**Affiliates.** We may also share your information among members of the Ritchie Bros. corporate family for purposes consistent with this Privacy Statement.  To the extent that our other corporate family members have access to your information, they will follow practices that are at least as restrictive as the practices described in this Privacy Statement.  They will also will comply with applicable laws governing the transmission of promotional communications and, at a minimum, give you an opportunity in any commercial email they send to choose not to receive such email messages in the future.

**Investigations and Law.** Regardless of the choices you make regarding your information (as described below) and to the extent permitted by applicable law, we may disclose information about you to third parties to:

  * Comply with law, in response to subpoenas, warrants, or court orders, or in connection with any legal process or cooperate with government or law enforcement officials or private parties, including laws outside of your country of residence;
  * Protect our rights, reputation, safety and property, or that of our customers or others;
  * Protect against legal liability;
  * Establish or exercise our rights to defend against legal claims; or
  * To investigate, prevent or take action regarding suspected illegal activities, suspected fraud, the rights, reputation, safety or property of us, customers or others, violation of our account terms and conditions, our policies or agreements or as otherwise required or permitted by applicable law.

**_California Privacy Rights_.** California law entitles residents to ask us once per calendar year for a notice describing what categories of personal information we share with third parties or with corporate affiliates (such as Ritchie Bros. EquipmentOne and Ritchie Bros. Financial Services) for those entities direct marketing purposes. We currently do not provide any personal information to unaffiliated third parties for their own direct marketing purposes. If you want to request a notice or have any questions about our privacy practices, please contact as noted below.

### Sharing

We may share aggregated demographic information with our trusted third party partners and affiliates. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person.

### Online Registration

To use certain areas of this website, participate in online bidding or subscribe to receive email notices, a user must first complete a registration form and provide contact information (such as name and email address). Registration will result in a membership record and unique cookie ID being created. Registration for an email notification subscription requires that registrants submit personal information including name, email address, industry and job title.  
Registration for access to certain areas of the website, including auction results and fleet valuator, requires registrants to submit personal information including that required for email notification subscription (above), plus company name, mailing address, and telephone number. Registration for access to online bidding services requires registrants to submit personal information including that required for the above purposes, plus physical address, personal identification (driver's license or passport ID), and tax information.  
Registration and the provision of this information are required to access these areas of the website. Visitors who do not input the required information will not have access to these areas.

### Special Offers, and Site and Service Updates

We may send registrants site and service announcement updates, and information regarding new or improved services and upcoming events that we think may be of interest to them. We may communicate with a user to provide requested services or with respect to their account via email or phone.

### Usage Data

Our website also collects other information through some of the features available on the site. Information including unique ID, access time, equipment search parameters and visitor feedback is collected. The online bidding and online consignment features collect access details including your assigned RBA bidder number and bid and consignment details.

### Cookies and Other Technologies

When you interact with our websites, we or our authorized third party service providers may place cookies, web beacons (also known as action tags or single-pixel gifs), and other non-cookie based technologies on your device to collect and store information that helps us track and analyze usage, provide a more efficient and personalized experience to our users, and to personalize online display advertising tailored to users' interests.  This information collected by us may be associated with personal information we already have or collect from other sources for the purposes noted above under "Information Use".  To opt out of our cookies used for online interest-based advertising, click here.

Some of these technologies may be permanently placed on your device until you choose to remove them (i.e. persistent cookies); while others are temporary and are removed after you close your browser (i.e. session cookies).  You are always free to block our cookies if your browser or device permits, although doing so may interfere with your use of some of our services' and websites' features or content.  For more information on how you can block, delete, or disable cookies, please review your specific browser or device settings.  You may also be able to browse our websites using your browser's anonymous usage setting (i.e. "Incognito" in Chrome).  Please review your browser settings for further details.  Please also note that you may choose to opt-out of some of these technologies as explained in "Choice/Opt Out" below.

Our use of these technologies falls into four categories:

1\. Operationally necessary – These technologies are used to permit access to our websites or services and use certain features such as maintaining logged-in status for your account while using a website, as well as enabling you to move around it and use its features.

2\. Functionality related – We use these technologies so we can remember your preferences while browsing websites and to provide enhanced and more personalized content and features, such as saved equipment searches. In order to permit your connection and use of our websites and services, we receive and record usage data about your device and browser (see above). If you access the website from a mobile or other device, we may collect a unique device identifier assigned to that device, geolocation data (where permitted in your device settings), or other transactional information for that device.

3\. Performance related – We and/or our service providers may use analytics and testing technologies to collect information about your usage and interaction with our services and websites, for instance web page views or interaction with a link or other content.  We use this information to understand overall usage patterns of our visitors and determine whether certain content is effective or not.  We do not permit any of these service providers to use any of your personal information collected on our websites for their own purposes.

4\. Advertising related – These technologies are used by us and our service providers to deliver advertising we believe is relevant to you and your interests.  For example, we may use first-party cookies and web beacons to deliver content, including ads, we believe are relevant to your interests, on the websites or on third party sites.  This means that when you are on websites other than our websites, you may be shown advertising based on your activity on our websites.  These technologies may also be used to help measure the effectiveness of our ad campaigns.  These technologies remember what you've looked at on our websites as well as, among other things, IP address, browser type, webpage visited prior to our websites, and the subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over.

Third-party advertisers and other organizations may also use their own cookies to collect information about your activities on our websites and/or the advertisements you have clicked on. This information, which may be combined with other information acquired from third parties, may be used by them to serve advertisements on our websites and third party sites that they believe are most likely to be of interest to you based on content you have viewed.  Third-party advertisers may also use this information to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to track aggregate usage statistics.  We may not control these third-party cookies and their use may be governed by the privacy policies of the third parties employing these cookies. To learn about these cookies and to disable or reject third-party cookies, please refer to the relevant third party's website or "Choice/Opt Out" below.

### Web Server Traffic Log Files

Web server logs collect visitor information including IP address, browser type and version, referring URLs, referring search engines and specified search strings. This information helps us design improvements to the services and navigational structure of our website.

### Children

RBA does not attempt to collect personal information from individuals under the age of 18.  
Note that RBA cannot always determine if a user of our website is a child under the age of 18.

### Links

This website contains links to other sites, including sites maintained by our corporate partners for the provision of online payment services and online shipping quotes. Please be aware that RBA is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to read the privacy statements of all websites that collect personal information.

### Paper Brochures

If a user wishes to subscribe to our brochure mailing list, we ask for contact information such as name and postal address.

### Surveys

Occasional surveys may be conducted on the RBA website. Survey information will be used to help us monitor and improve the use of this site and our services.

### Security

While we take reasonable administrative, technical and physical measures to protect the information you submit or that we collect online and offline against loss, theft and unauthorized use, disclosure, or modification, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.  No Internet, email or mobile application transmission is ever fully secure or error free.  If you believe your account has been abused, please contact us at [csg@rbauction.com](mailto:csg@rbauction.com).

### Correction/Updating Personal Information

A registrant may change or update its personal information or remove itself from our service, by emailing us at [csg@rbauction.com](mailto:csg@rbauction.com).

### Choice / Opt-Out

You have a choice about how we use your personal information to communicate with you and how we provide relevant advertising.

**1\. Communication**

When registering for access to the My Account section of the website, users can select or de-select the checkbox that asks if they would like periodic email marketing notices (e.g. email newsletter and e-brochures). However, as mentioned in the Special Offers, and Site and Service Updates section, some messages are not optional for website registrants.

Users can also unsubscribe from non-optional emails by clicking the unsubscribe link in any marketing email they receive.

**2\. Advertising & Analytics**

We use the following service providers to assist us with serving interest based ads and to analyze your interactions with our services and websites using the technologies described above under "Cookies and Other Technologies".

_Google Analytics_ – These cookies allow us to understand how you use and interact with our services.  If you don't want data to be collected and reported by Google Analytics, you can opt-out by installing a browser add-on.  Visit the [Google Analytics opt-out page](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881?hl=en) for more information.

_Google DoubleClick and AdSense_ – We use these services to serve advertisements we think may be of interest to you based on your previous interactions with our websites and your activity across multiple other websites.  You may opt-out of the DoubleClick cookie for interest based advertising by visiting Google's [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/safetycenter/tools/#manage-your-ads-preferences) and changing your settings.  There you will also find instructions to permanently opt-out through the use of an installed browser plug-in.

_Simplifi and Lotame_ – These service providers assist us in our digital advertising campaigns and better understand the effectiveness of our digital ads.  You can find more information about their privacy practices by reviewing their respective privacy policies – click [here](https://www.simpli.fi/ad-serving-privacy-policy-3/) for Simplifi and click [here](https://www.lotame.com/legal/) for Lotame.  You can opt-out of the collection of information by these service providers by visiting their respective opt-out webpages and following the relevant instructions – click [here](https://app.simpli.fi/opt-out) for Simplifi and click [here](https://www.lotame.com/opt-out-preference-manager/) for Lotame.

_Hotjar –_ We use this service to help us analyze and test your interactions with our websites. The information collected is then used to optimize your experience while using the Service.  For more information on Hotjar's privacy practices, please click [here](https://www.hotjar.com/privacy), or to opt-out of further data collection, follow the instructions [here](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out).

_Conversant_ – We use the services of Conversant to collect and use anonymous information about your visits to and interactions with the Website through the use of technologies such as cookies to personalize online ads for goods and services.  Certain limited, non-sensitive personal information collected by us that relates to your transactional history is also shared with an affiliate of Conversant for anonymization to enable our use of Conversant's services.  We take appropriate steps to ensure that the recipient safeguards this personal information and uses the information only for authorized purposes.  For more information about Conversant's privacy practices, please click [here](http://www.conversantmedia.com/legal/privacy), or to opt-out of further anonymous data collection by Conversant, follow the instructions [here](http://optout.conversantmedia.com/).  To opt-out of our sharing of your limited, non-sensitive personal information, please contact us at [customercare@equipmentone.com](mailto:customercare@equipmentone.com) _._

Note that opt-out choices selected above may be browser and device specific.  As well, deleting cookies can remove your opt-out preferences, so you may need to periodically refresh your opt-out preferences.

Please also note that opting-out of our interest based advertising is not the same thing as opting out of ads.  You will still see ads, and you may even see our ads, however, they will be random.  For more information about targeting and advertising cookies and how you can opt-out from certain third parties generally, visit:

  * Network Advertising Initiative: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>
  * Digital Advertising Alliance: <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>
  * European Digital Advertising Alliance: <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>

To set "Limit Ad Tracking" on various iOS devices, please [click here](http://support.apple.com/kb/ht4228).

To opt-out of interest-based ads on Android, open your Google Settings app > Ads > Enable "Opt out of interest-based advertising"

**_Do Not Track_.** At this time, we do not respond to "Do Not Track" signals sent from web browsers.

### Notification of Changes & Acceptance of Privacy Statement

By using the RBA website and services, you signify your acceptance of this Privacy Statement.  
We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Statement at any time. Your continued use of any portion of the RBA website following notification or posting of such changes will constitute your acceptance of those changes.

If we change our privacy practices, we will post those changes to our Privacy Statement web page and update the date listed on the links to it, as well as on the statement itself. We will post those changes so users are always aware of what personal information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We may from time to time provide notice of changes to this Privacy Statement by email or mail, or to other contact information provided by you. We use personal information in accordance with the Privacy Statement under which the personal information was collected. If at any point we decide to use personal information in a manner different from that currently stated, we will notify users. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their personal information in this different manner.

If you have questions or concerns about this privacy statement, please send an email to [webmaster@rbauction.com](mailto:webmaster@rbauction.com).

Last Revised: August 17, 2016

Node: dc1vplfry06.rbauction.net
